Today we will talk about the
difference between Advantage's new plan 2022 and the old plan. There are many people
who are
holding the old version of ICICI Lombard Health Advantage, so it is
important for them to know what is in the new version.
Next, when you
renew the policy, you will also be
upgraded to the new version. Next,
I would like to tell you about the on-date difference,
what all things they have changed and
what those things mean for you.
Before starting the video, I would
like to introduce myself. My name is
Ruling. I am a Certified Financial
Planner. I make videos for you every week so that
your personal financial life
becomes easy and happy because
this is also the tagline of our company, Creating a Wealth of
Happiness. And a quick reminder, if
you have not yet subscribed to our channel, do
subscribe and you give me the right
information and the right time. Let's move on to the
video. ICICI Lombard Health
Comparison Between Old Variant and New
Variant. The biggest difference which was there earlier was
ICICI  Lombard Health Advantage has
three variants, three options,
which you can choose as per your need, which were
Prime, Pix and Royal,
now there is only a single option of Apex
Plus, so there was a lot of confusion about
which plan to take, what is covered in it,
what to do and so on, so now we have made it a single
plan of this Epic Plus.
In the earlier plan, you had the option of many
options, actually in that plan, you
can modify many things as per your requirement,
now it has been fixed here, so the pre and
post hospitalization option which was 360 in the old plan,
you can upgrade it to 69, which means
30 days free and 60 days post the basic, if
you want to upgrade it, you can take it to 60 days
free on 90 days post.
In the new variant which is 2022
ICC People Healthier Advantage, Apex
Plus, it has 60 days fixed pre and
180 days fixed post hospitalization
number of days opt benefit.  If we talk about it, then
OPD benefit was optional in the old plan,
you could add it, which was 5%
off. There is no OPD benefit option here,
meaning it is not a plan option, but if you
want to add it, then there is a rider which is called rider,
you can add it. In ICICI Lombard
New Health Advantage, the old plan did
not have the same features as the old plan, which if
hospital benefit of more than 10 days is
given, it is available in the new plan.
Some features in the old plan were
optional, which you could add by paying an additional premium,
like domestic air
ambulance. Domestic air ambulance was
not a part of the policy, you could add it by paying an extra
premium. Now, domestic air ambulance is
inbuilt and is a part of your policy. Home
care treatment was not covered in the old plan,
meaning if you want to have a hospital session at home, it was
not covered in the old plan. In the
new ICICI Lombard Health Advantage, it is
covered with 5% and time shot maximum Rs
25,000. Unlimited tele consultations through Il
Tech Care App are available in the old plan.  It was not available in the old variant, it
is available in the new variant, you can get unlimited tele consultation through I
will take care of you. Now let's
talk about worldwide coverage, so
worldwide coverage is also a feature that
many people ask for in their policy, there was
no option of worldwide coverage in the old plan,
I am talking about ICICI Lombard Advantage,
they have another plan ICICI Lombard
Health Plus, in that there is an option of worldwide coverage, but
not in Health, now
in ICICI Lombard Advantage 2022, worldwide coverage has been
included, it is inbuilt, for 25
lakhs, short, means if the amount is above 25 lakhs,
then cashless worldwide coverage has been included in it, in
which there is 10% cover and their
partner is International Partner, through which this international partner
will manage the file of the international, all other
features are in it, some riders are there
in the old policy as well, like maternity
rider, critical illness and personal
accident, those riders are there in the new policy as well  It is
available from ₹1.5 lakh. There has been a call change. Earlier the
waiting period for pre-existing diseases was
24 months. You had the option to make it
36 ​​or 48 months.
To reduce your premium, it is fixed at
24 months. Now, if all these changes have been made, then there must have been a
difference in some costs as well, like your
worldwide coverage has been added, emergency
ambulance has been added mainly. So,
how much difference has there been in the cost? I
would like to tell you, if you have a policy of less than 25 lakhs, then
this
cost will increase by approximately
five to six percent. You will have to pay 5 to 6% more than the earlier cost.
In ICICI Lombard Health Advantage Variant 2022, if you have a policy of more than 25 lakhs,
because worldwide
coverage is included in it, then there is an
approximate 11 to 12% increase in the cost.
This is on every 8 slabs and its premium is also the same as it
was in the old one. Yours will
increase as per 8 slabs, rest you  If you
want to see the detailed video, then the
detailed video of both is available on our channel
ICICI Lombard Health Advantage Old
Variant and ICICI Lombard Health
Advantage Variant 2022, you can ask any questions regarding
these two plans
and as I said the
old plan has been discontinued,
on renewal you will be shifted to the new plan only, so that is why it was
necessary to make this video so that you know
what changes are there for you in the new plan, if you want to ask anything
you can ask us, our
WhatsApp number email ID is mentioned below,
quick reminder before leaving, if you have
not yet subscribed to our channel, then
subscribe so like you get the right
information, we will meet you
in the next video, stay and take care, bye bye, so
for them to know this
and quick reminder, so you can do as per
your convenience, quick reminder before leaving,
if you have not yet subscribed to our channel